Recently, Australia just had their
biggest gaming convention of the year,
PAX, the Penny Arcade Expo. And while I
used to attend these for all the awesome
video games, this year I only had one
thing on my mind, Magic the Gathering.
And after that weekend, something was
rekindled within me. For this year's
packs, Magic was a big focus. Gavin
Verhe, principal Magic the Gathering
designer at Wizards of the Coast was
giving the keynote speech and we also
had American content creator Ben Baitman
flown in. There was also a showcase of
other Australian MTG talent, Good Games,
Moley, Cozy Magic Club, After Hours, and
Base Deck Department.
On the Friday, I started packs off by
learning to play the new League of
Legends TCG Riftbound with none other
than Instant Speed MTG Newsman, Toa MTG.
It's a pretty interesting game and feels
a lot like Commander. It's probably
something I'll make a video about in the
near future.
Then later that evening, thanks to Gavin
himself, I was invited to participate in
Ben Baitman's Chaos Draft. Chaos Draft
is where you take random boosters from
Magic's history and draft with all of
them. We had everything from Magic 30 to
Homelands and Fallen Empires. We all
gentlemans agreed that the winner of the
draft would get to keep all of the cards
we opened that night. Now, I did manage
to draft an awesome red green aggro deck
with Fireball and Overrun, but I'm
really bad at social media and I didn't
take any pictures of the deck. The deck
did pretty well and the only loss I had
that night was against Gavin who beat me
with my own cards thanks to the black
cat cunning thief that he drafted. So,
while I didn't walk away with a stack of
cards, I did have a lot of fun.
On the Saturday, after designing some
cards with Gavin, there was a porpa
tournament. Porper, for those who don't
know, is a 60c card format where the
only cards you're allowed to play are
commons. And after finding out that
there was a Porper Tron deck, I quickly
pulled one together and signed up. The
goal of my deck was simple. Assemble
Tron and then through the deck's
multitudes of card draw, assemble the
combo of Ashnod's Altar, two copies of
Mer Retriever, and then either Pack Doll
Terror for infinite damage or Golem
Foundry for infinite creatures. I ended
up going 211 in the tournament, only
losing to my worst matchup in round one,
a Mardu Synthesizer deck that was main
decking cleansing wildfires. I'm so glad
I played in this tournament. Thanks to
this and the draft that I did on Friday,
I realized how much I miss playing 1v1
60card formats. Standard has been
absolutely soul draining, but playing
porpa was so refreshing. You're probably
going to see me talk a little bit more
about porpa in the near future. I have
no idea what that content looks like
yet, but stay tuned.
On Sunday, things were a lot more
relaxed. I stopped over at the Cozy
Magic Club meetup and scored some
awesome sleeves from Palms Off Gaming,
snuck in a quick game of Commander, and
then headed off to Ben Baitman's panel
about making a career for yourself in
Magic the Gathering.
Turns out the answer is post more
content. Yeah, we'll see how that goes.
There was an awesome PAX afterparty
hosted at the Tessy Pearl, but because
I'm bad at social media, I didn't take
any pictures. But trust me, it was a lot
of fun. A couple of dinners later, and
that's my magic pack well and truly
dusted. It's great to see that PAX had a
focus on MTG this year. It personally
feels like it was a real success. So,
here's hoping it will be bigger and
better next year.
Have you ever been to PAX before? What
do you think of the PAPA format? Let me
know in the comments below. Thanks for
watching and I'll see you in the next
one.